<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <UnfinishedHealthItemBionicAnimal.label>unfinished animal bionic</UnfinishedHealthItemBionicAnimal.label>
  <UnfinishedHealthItemBionicAnimal.description>An unfinished animal bionic.</UnfinishedHealthItemBionicAnimal.description>
  <BionicTailAnimal.label>bionic animal tail</BionicTailAnimal.label>
  <BionicTailAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal tail. Silenced mini-servos give great strength, while the biogel nerve-link gives exquisite control. A lattice-dust healing system allows it to recover from damage. It is better than a biological tail in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicTailAnimal.description>
  <BionicEyeAnimal.label>bionic animal eye</BionicEyeAnimal.label>
  <BionicEyeAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal eye. With its biogel nerve-link, internal signal pre-processor, and wide-spectrum sensors, it is better than a biological eye in almost every way. A lattice-dust healing system allows it to recover from damage. Fits all animals.</BionicEyeAnimal.description>
  <BionicArmAnimal.label>bionic animal arm</BionicArmAnimal.label>
  <BionicArmAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal arm. Silenced mini-servos give great strength, while the biogel nerve-link gives exquisite control. A lattice-dust healing system allows it to recover from damage. It is better than a biological arm in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicArmAnimal.description>
  <BionicLegAnimal.label>bionic animal leg</BionicLegAnimal.label>
  <BionicLegAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal leg. With its biogel nerve-link, powerful mini-servos, and lattice-dust healing system, it is better than a biological leg in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicLegAnimal.description>
  <BionicSpineAnimal.label>bionic animal spine</BionicSpineAnimal.label>
  <BionicSpineAnimal.description>A biogel nerve bundle runs down an articulated plasteel core, surrounded by a lattice-dust healing system. It matches the performance of a biological spine. Fits all animals.</BionicSpineAnimal.description>
  <BionicHeartAnimal.label>bionic animal heart</BionicHeartAnimal.label>
  <BionicHeartAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal heart. It has synthetic muscle fibers for a realistic heartbeat, plus a high-flow pump for rapid circulation during high stress. It is better than a biological heart in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicHeartAnimal.description>
  <BionicStomachAnimal.label>bionic animal stomach</BionicStomachAnimal.label>
  <BionicStomachAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal stomach. A set of sensors and chemical synthesizers efficiently digest nearly any energy-bearing foodstuff. An integrated lattice-dust healing system automatically repairs any damage caused by the powerful acids. It is better than a biological stomach in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicStomachAnimal.description>
  <BionicEarAnimal.label>bionic animal ear</BionicEarAnimal.label>
  <BionicEarAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal ear. A collection of invisible subdermal microphones capture sound and transmit it to a biogel nerve interface that links directly with the auditory nerve. It's sensitive enough to hear a cat before you see it, can't be damaged by loud noise, and automatically tunes itself to pick out meaningful sounds in noisy environments. Fits all animals.</BionicEarAnimal.description>
  <BionicTongueAnimal.label>bionic animal tongue</BionicTongueAnimal.label>
  <BionicTongueAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal tongue replacement. Made of synthetic smooth-fibers and connected through a neurogel interface, it can match the performance of a natural tongue in eating and tasting. Fits all animals.</BionicTongueAnimal.description>
  <BionicJawAnimal.label>bionic animal jaw</BionicJawAnimal.label>
  <BionicJawAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal jaw. Silenced mini-servos give great jaw strength A lattice-dust healing system allows it to recover from damage. It is better than a biological jaw in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicJawAnimal.description>
  <UnfinishedHealthItemProstheticAnimal.label>unfinished prosthetic animal</UnfinishedHealthItemProstheticAnimal.label>
  <UnfinishedHealthItemProstheticAnimal.description>An unfinished prosthetic animal.</UnfinishedHealthItemProstheticAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticTailAnimal.label>prosthetic animal tail</SimpleProstheticTailAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticTailAnimal.description>An animal tail prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's tail. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticTailAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticLegAnimal.label>prosthetic animal leg</SimpleProstheticLegAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticLegAnimal.description>An animal leg prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's leg. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticLegAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticArmAnimal.label>prosthetic animal arm</SimpleProstheticArmAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticArmAnimal.description>An animal arm prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's arm. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticArmAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticHeartAnimal.label>prosthetic animal heart</SimpleProstheticHeartAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticHeartAnimal.description>An animal heart prosthesis. It contains an electric motor that pumps blood smoothly around the body. The user's owners often report them looking tired, but it's better than the alternative. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticHeartAnimal.description>
  <CochlearImplantAnimal.label>animal cochlear implant</CochlearImplantAnimal.label>
  <CochlearImplantAnimal.description>An implant which replaces normal hearing, made with animals in mind. An external microphone transmits a sound signal to electrodes wrapped around the inner ear's auditory sensing nerves. The electrodes stimulate the nerves according to the sound, creating a sensation of hearing. It's not as good as a natural ear, but it's a lot better than being deaf. Fits all animals.</CochlearImplantAnimal.description>
  <SyntheticLungAnimal.label>synthetic animal lung</SyntheticLungAnimal.label>
  <SyntheticLungAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal lung. It has synthetic muscle fibers for a realistic breathing, plus a high-flow pump for rapid deep breathes during intensive activities. It is better than a biological lung in almost every way. Fits all animals.</SyntheticLungAnimal.description>
  <SyntheticLiverAnimal.label>synthetic animal liver</SyntheticLiverAnimal.label>
  <SyntheticLiverAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal liver. A set of sensors and chemical synthesizers monitors and replicate the liver's role in metabolism, instantly adapting to changes in the body. It is better than a biological liver in almost every way. Fits all animals.</SyntheticLiverAnimal.description>
  <SyntheticKidneyAnimal.label>synthetic animal kidney</SyntheticKidneyAnimal.label>
  <SyntheticKidneyAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal kidney. A set of sensors and synthetic filters that efficiently removes waste products from the blood. It is better than a biological kidney in almost every way. Fits all animals.</SyntheticKidneyAnimal.description>
  <LightReceptorAnimal.label>animal light receptor</LightReceptorAnimal.label>
  <LightReceptorAnimal.description>An eye prosthesis make with animals in mind. The optic nerves recieve stimulation from the light sensors and signal processors, creating a sensation of vision. It's not as good as a natural eye, but it's a lot better than being blind. Fits all animals.</LightReceptorAnimal.description>
  <SimpleSpineAnimal.label>replacement animal spine</SimpleSpineAnimal.label>
  <SimpleSpineAnimal.description>An animal spine prosthesis. Highly advanced for its time, can be considered as an early bionic prototype with the first sophisticated application of neural interface in a prosthesis. Still, it is inferior to a real spine. Fits all animals.</SimpleSpineAnimal.description>
  <HydraulicJawAnimal.label>hydraulic animal jaw</HydraulicJawAnimal.label>
  <HydraulicJawAnimal.description>An animal jaw prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Food is crushed and chewed more efficiently. Fits all animals.</HydraulicJawAnimal.description>
  <ArtificialNoseAnimal.label>artificial animal nose</ArtificialNoseAnimal.label>
  <ArtificialNoseAnimal.description>An animal nose prosthesis. Used to cover where the missing nose was on the face. Fits all animals.</ArtificialNoseAnimal.description>
  <SurrogateLungAnimal.label>surrogate animal lung</SurrogateLungAnimal.label>
  <SurrogateLungAnimal.description>An animal lung prosthesis. It contains an electric motor that expands and contracts the prosthesis for gas exchanges, simulating breathing. The user's owners often report them looking tired, but it's better than the alternative. Fits all animals.</SurrogateLungAnimal.description>
  <SurrogateStomachAnimal.label>surrogate animal stomach</SurrogateStomachAnimal.label>
  <SurrogateStomachAnimal.description>An animal stomach prosthesis. It contains chemical synthesizers that can digest most foodstuff, the strength of them is limited as to not dissolve the prosthesis itself. It is rather inefficient at the job, but it is better than the alternative. Fits all animals.</SurrogateStomachAnimal.description>
  <SurrogateLiverAnimal.label>surrogate animal liver</SurrogateLiverAnimal.label>
  <SurrogateLiverAnimal.description>An animal liver prosthesis. It contains chemical synthesizers to imitate the liver's role in metabolism. The user's owners often report them looking slightly unwell, but it's better than the alternative. Fits all animals.</SurrogateLiverAnimal.description>
  <SurrogateKidneyAnimal.label>surrogate animal kidney</SurrogateKidneyAnimal.label>
  <SurrogateKidneyAnimal.description>An animal kidney prosthesis. It contains artificial filters and removes waste products from the blood. The user's owners often report them looking slightly unwell, but it's better than the alternative. Fits all animals.</SurrogateKidneyAnimal.description>
  <BrainStimulatorAnimal.label>animal brain stimulator</BrainStimulatorAnimal.label>
  <BrainStimulatorAnimal.description>A small device that does its best to stimulate the remaining areas of an animal's brain. Recommended for severe brain damage only. Requires brain surgery research before installing. Fits all animals.</BrainStimulatorAnimal.description>
  <BionicHeartAnimal.label.label>synthetic animal heart</BionicHeartAnimal.label.label>
  <BionicStomachAnimal.label.label>synthetic animal stomach</BionicStomachAnimal.label.label>
  <SimpleProstheticHeartAnimal.label.label>surrogate animal heart</SimpleProstheticHeartAnimal.label.label>
  <BionicPawAnimal.label>bionic animal paw</BionicPawAnimal.label>
  <BionicPawAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal paw. With its biogel nerve-link, powerful mini-servos, and lattice-dust healing system, it is better than a biological paw in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicPawAnimal.description>
  <BionicHoofAnimal.label>bionic animal hoof</BionicHoofAnimal.label>
  <BionicHoofAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal hoof. With its biogel nerve-link, powerful mini-servos, and lattice-dust healing system, it is better than a biological hoof in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicHoofAnimal.description>
  <BionicFootAnimal.label>bionic animal foot</BionicFootAnimal.label>
  <BionicFootAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal foot. With its biogel nerve-link, powerful mini-servos, and lattice-dust healing system, it is better than a biological foot in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicFootAnimal.description>
  <BionicToeAnimal.label>bionic animal toe</BionicToeAnimal.label>
  <BionicToeAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal toe. Delicate sensors and high-speed wireless transmitters running through the thick, yet lightweight plasteel casing ensure the best precision and grip, far surpassing that of a biological toe. Fits all animals.</BionicToeAnimal.description>
  <BionicHandAnimal.label>bionic animal hand</BionicHandAnimal.label>
  <BionicHandAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal hand. With its biogel nerve-link, powerful mini-servos, and lattice-dust healing system, it is better than a biological hand in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicHandAnimal.description>
  <BionicFingerAnimal.label>bionic animal finger</BionicFingerAnimal.label>
  <BionicFingerAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal finger. Delicate sensors and high-speed wireless transmitters running through the thick, yet lightweight plasteel casing ensure the best precision and grip, far surpassing that of a biological finger. Fits all animals.</BionicFingerAnimal.description>
  <BionicClawAnimal.label>bionic animal claw</BionicClawAnimal.label>
  <BionicClawAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal claw. Delicate sensors and high-speed wireless transmitters running through the thick, yet lightweight plasteel casing ensure the best precision and grip, far surpassing that of a biological claw. Fits all animals.</BionicClawAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticHandAnimal.label>prosthetic animal hand</SimpleProstheticHandAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticHandAnimal.description>An animal hand prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's hand. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticHandAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticFingerAnimal.label>prosthetic animal finger</SimpleProstheticFingerAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticFingerAnimal.description>Archaic and crude replacement for lost animal fingers. Not terribly efficient and certainly not comfortable, but gets the job done. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticFingerAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticFootAnimal.label>prosthetic animal foot</SimpleProstheticFootAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticFootAnimal.description>An animal foot prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's foot. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticFootAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticToeAnimal.label>prosthetic animal toe</SimpleProstheticToeAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticToeAnimal.description>Archaic and crude replacement for lost animal toes. Inefficient and uncomfortable, they generate a lot of noise while walking, but they get the job done. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticToeAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticPawAnimal.label>prosthetic animal paw</SimpleProstheticPawAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticPawAnimal.description>An animal paw prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's paw. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticPawAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticHoofAnimal.label>prosthetic animal hoof</SimpleProstheticHoofAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticHoofAnimal.description>An animal hoof prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's hoof. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticHoofAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProstheticClawAnimal.label>prosthetic animal claw</SimpleProstheticClawAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticClawAnimal.description>An animal claw prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's claw. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticClawAnimal.description>
  <BionicForearmAnimal.label>bionic animal forearm</BionicForearmAnimal.label>
  <BionicForearmAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal forearm. Silenced mini-servos give great strength, while the biogel nerve-link gives exquisite control. A lattice-dust healing system allows it to recover from damage. It is better than a biological arm in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicForearmAnimal.description>
  <BionicInternalSupportAnimal.label>bionic animal internal support</BionicInternalSupportAnimal.label>
  <BionicInternalSupportAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal internal support. Useful replacement to have on hand for when an internal component of a bionic prosthesis breaks. Fits all animals.</BionicInternalSupportAnimal.description>
  <Bionic_RG_FootClaw.label>bionic animal foot claw</Bionic_RG_FootClaw.label>
  <Bionic_RG_FootClaw.description>An advanced artificial animal foot claw. With its biogel nerve-link, powerful mini-servos, lattice-dust healing system, and sharp plasteel blade, it is better than a biological foot claw in almost every way. Fits all animals.</Bionic_RG_FootClaw.description>
  <SimpleProstheticForearmAnimal.label>prosthetic animal forearm</SimpleProstheticForearmAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticForearmAnimal.description>An animal forearm prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's forearm. Fits all animals.</SimpleProstheticForearmAnimal.description>
  <SimpleProsthetic_RG_FootClaw.label>prosthetic animal foot claw</SimpleProsthetic_RG_FootClaw.label>
  <SimpleProsthetic_RG_FootClaw.description>An animal foot claw prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's foot claw. Fits all animals.</SimpleProsthetic_RG_FootClaw.description>
  <SimpleProstheticWingAnimal.label>prosthetic animal wing</SimpleProstheticWingAnimal.label>
  <SimpleProstheticWingAnimal.description>A prosthetic animal wing. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints and artifical membrane allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real animal's wing.</SimpleProstheticWingAnimal.description>
  <BionicWingAnimal.label>bionic animal wing</BionicWingAnimal.label>
  <BionicWingAnimal.description>An advanced artificial animal wing. With its biogel nerve-link, lightweight synthetic membrane, and lattice-dust healing system, it is better than a biological wing in almost every way. Fits all animals.</BionicWingAnimal.description>
</LanguageData>