<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <PRF_AutomaticFarmingI.label>automated agriculture</PRF_AutomaticFarmingI.label>
  <PRF_AutomaticFarmingI.description>농업용 드론은 농업 운영 최적화, 농작물 생산 증가, 작물 성장 감시 등을 돕기 위해 사용되는 무인 항공기입니다. 센서와 디지털 이미징 기능은 농부들에게 그들의 밭에 대한 더 풍부한 그림을 제공할 수 있게 되었습니다.</PRF_AutomaticFarmingI.description>
  <PRF_AnimalStations.label>동물 스테이션 I</PRF_AnimalStations.label>
  <PRF_AnimalStations.description>동물 스테이션 1단계 기술을 통해 수확 가능한 동물에게서 자동으로 자원을 수확할 수 있습니다.</PRF_AnimalStations.description>
  <PRF_AutomaticFarmingII.label>improved automated agriculture</PRF_AutomaticFarmingII.label>
  <PRF_AutomaticFarmingII.description>Additional improvements to automated agriculture now greatly increase crop production and a more careful tending to your farm by improved labor drones.</PRF_AutomaticFarmingII.description>
  <PRF_AnimalStationsII.label>동물 스테이션 II</PRF_AnimalStationsII.label>
  <PRF_AnimalStationsII.description>The second tier of animal station technology allows for more animal gathering and automated animal slaughtering and breeding control.</PRF_AnimalStationsII.description>
  <PRF_AutomaticFarmingIII.label>advanced automated agriculture</PRF_AutomaticFarmingIII.label>
  <PRF_AutomaticFarmingIII.description>With advanced use of mechanites and improved AI control, cultivators can now work even without drones or with a buffed drone version. Sprinklers also work faster now.</PRF_AutomaticFarmingIII.description>
  <PRF_AnimalStationsIII.label>동물 스테이션 III</PRF_AnimalStationsIII.label>
  <PRF_AnimalStationsIII.description>The third tier of animal station technology allows for more and better automated animal gathering and control.</PRF_AnimalStationsIII.description>
  <PRF_SelfCooking.label>자동 조리</PRF_SelfCooking.label>
  <PRF_SelfCooking.description>The first tier of automated cooking research allows you to make buildings that can cook meals themselves. It's just like your dedicated cook, but these devices won't have mental breaks for silly reasons.\nThis one will unlock simple foodstuff and dedicated machines, a good entry into automation.</PRF_SelfCooking.description>
  <PRF_SelfCookingII.label>improved self-cooking</PRF_SelfCookingII.label>
  <PRF_SelfCookingII.description>자동 요리의 두 번째 단계를 통해 우리는 제작기에서 더 나은 품질의 음식을 생산할 수 있습니다.</PRF_SelfCookingII.description>
  <PRF_MetalRefining.label>metal refining</PRF_MetalRefining.label>
  <PRF_MetalRefining.description>A metal refinery able to produce rare metals through polymer lamination by combining chemfuel with steel to create plasteel.</PRF_MetalRefining.description>
  <PRF_MachineLearning.label>complex machine applications</PRF_MachineLearning.label>
  <PRF_MachineLearning.description>기계에게 스스로 능력을 향상시키는 방법을 가르칩니다. 어떤 계획서라도 배울 수 있는 스마트 조립기에 유용합니다.</PRF_MachineLearning.description>
  <PRF_MagneticTape.label>자기 테이프</PRF_MagneticTape.label>
  <PRF_MagneticTape.description>오디오 녹음에 사용되는 특수 산업용 테이프로, 중요한 지침 및 일반 정보를 보관하는 데 유용한 방법입니다.</PRF_MagneticTape.description>
  <PRF_MagneticTape.discoveredLetterTitle>About: Intro to recipe database</PRF_MagneticTape.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_MagneticTape.discoveredLetterText>You have learned how to make and use old-school magnetic tape to store instructions.\nMake data disks at the machining table.\nThis is used to import recipes from any workbench into your recipe database.\nYou do so by placing it near a workbench and clicking import on those recipes you want it to store. Afterward, you can move it to another workbench and copy more. Or you can move it to the assembler you want to link to it.\nRecipes will be stored forever in your database, and you can safely move it around. Please note that if you remove it from your assemblers, they will lose their configured bills.</PRF_MagneticTape.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_UniversalAutocrafting.label>범용 자동 제작</PRF_UniversalAutocrafting.label>
  <PRF_UniversalAutocrafting.description>레시피 데이터베이스를 통해 주어진 레시피를 만들 수 있는 건물을 만드세요. 당신의 헌신적인 제작자들처럼 그들은 플레이크 과다 복용으로 잠들거나 죽지 않습니다.</PRF_UniversalAutocrafting.description>
  <PRF_UniversalAutocrafting.discoveredLetterTitle>정보: 조립기 소개</PRF_UniversalAutocrafting.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_UniversalAutocrafting.discoveredLetterText>You have unlocked your first real type assembler, this is basically a universal machine that can produce anything your workbenches can do. You just copy bills with a recipe database and place it near your assembler to show recipes.\nPlease note that it CAN'T return the same item again so mods like Mend and Recycle will not work on assemblers, as they destroy products they take in.\n\nThis assembler has stats set to 10 which means it can ONLY see recipes with a required level of 10 or less in the database. If you upgrade to the next tier it will be smarter and have a higher skill level.\nThis assembler has a fixed speed and will not get better over time as the next tier will.</PRF_UniversalAutocrafting.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_SelfCorrectingAssemblers.label>intelligent assemblers</PRF_SelfCorrectingAssemblers.label>
  <PRF_SelfCorrectingAssemblers.description>시간이 지남에 따라 천천히 제작 속도를 향상시키는 새로운 유형의 조립기를 만드는 방법을 배웁니다.</PRF_SelfCorrectingAssemblers.description>
  <PRF_SelfCorrectingAssemblersII.label>quantum intelligent assemblers</PRF_SelfCorrectingAssemblersII.label>
  <PRF_SelfCorrectingAssemblersII.description>두 가지 새로운 유형의 적응형 조립기를 만드는 방법을 배웁니다. 하나는 초고속이지만 매우 낮은 품질의 물품을 생산하고, 다른 하나는 느리지만 좋은 품질로 시작합니다.</PRF_SelfCorrectingAssemblersII.description>
  <PRF_EnhancedBatteries.label>electrical batteries</PRF_EnhancedBatteries.label>
  <PRF_EnhancedBatteries.description>효율적인 전기 저장을 위해 대형 축전지를 만듭니다. 이 첫 번째 단계는 4k 축전지의 잠금을 해제합니다.</PRF_EnhancedBatteries.description>
  <PRF_LargeBatteries.label>improved batteries</PRF_LargeBatteries.label>
  <PRF_LargeBatteries.description>효율적인 전기 저장을 위해 더 큰 축전지를 만듭니다. 두 번째 단계는 16k 및 64k 축전지의 잠금을 해제합니다.</PRF_LargeBatteries.description>
  <PRF_VeryLargeBatteries.label>advanced batteries</PRF_VeryLargeBatteries.label>
  <PRF_VeryLargeBatteries.description>배터리 저장 기술의 한계를 뛰어넘고 대용량 전력 저장을 위한 고효율 256k 축전리를 만듭니다.</PRF_VeryLargeBatteries.description>
  <PRF_CoreTierO.label>clockwork principle</PRF_CoreTierO.label>
  <PRF_CoreTierO.description>Early industrialization, teaches you how to set up a more advanced way of gathering resources and process them into more useful things. Trash, raw materials, or scrap metal goes in one side and useful products come out the other.\nThese very early devices are made with cogs and chutes and are powered by wood and coal.</PRF_CoreTierO.description>
  <PRF_CoreTierO.discoveredLetterTitle>Early automation</PRF_CoreTierO.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_CoreTierO.discoveredLetterText>Welcome to Project RimFactory Beta!\n\nWe invite you on a trip through automation, starting with wood and coal-fueled smelters and advancing through AI-controlled self-improving assemblers.\n\nGeneral Usage: Store materials in the white designation input area for the machine to consume. After a bit of work, the machine will place the finished product on its yellow output tile.\n\nThe oldest known clockwork machine is the Antikythera mechanism, found in 1901 in a shipwreck dated 50 BC and Greek in origin. A series of 30 gears was used to predict eclipses and other astronomical phenomena as well as the passage of years. Advanced clockwork mechanisms reached new heights in Europe during the 1800s, and even today automation without computers is used in industry.\n\nCode by:spdskatr, Nobo, Abnerchen, Little White Mouse, Madara Uchiha, Sn1p3rr3c0n.\nArt by: ShotgunFrenzy, Chicken Plucker, Xen, Scythe, totoBrother, "Unknown Alien", Argon, spdskatr, Thornsworth.\nTested by Malkav, Extrien, Daemon976, AerosAtar, and the mandatory Steam volunteers.\nTranslated by: Natsu_Zirok, 十里小飞, AbnerChen, Lucas559-noob.\nSpecial thanks Thornsworth and Nobo, who are no longer with us.\nRest In Productivity.</PRF_CoreTierO.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_CoreTierI.label>오일러의 공식</PRF_CoreTierI.label>
  <PRF_CoreTierI.description>Leonard Euler developed mathematical systems for interactions between physics, geometry and algebra.\nWith these formulas, automated production of basic materials such as stone bricks and simple art is possible.\nPlace items within the white designation for the bills to consume, they will be output to the adjustable green tile.</PRF_CoreTierI.description>
  <PRF_CoreTierI.discoveredLetterTitle>True automation begins</PRF_CoreTierI.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_CoreTierI.discoveredLetterText>Leonard Euler developed mathematical systems for interactions between physics, geometry and algebra.\nWith these formulas, automated production of basic materials such as stone bricks and simple art is possible.\nPlace items within the white designation for the bills to consume, they will be output to the adjustable green tile</PRF_CoreTierI.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_CoreTierII.label>machine learning</PRF_CoreTierII.label>
  <PRF_CoreTierII.description>A machine that can predict outcomes will solve many of the design flaws we have been facing. Imagine a machine that could improve itself...\nWe will need a factory research terminal linked to our hi-tech research bench to go further.</PRF_CoreTierII.description>
  <PRF_CoreTierII.discoveredLetterTitle>기계 학습</PRF_CoreTierII.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_CoreTierII.discoveredLetterText>The mathematical models developed in the 1700s began an industrial revolution all over the world, a series of gears and pressurization allowed the mass processing of basic materials with coal and electricity.\nMoritz von Jacobi managed to propel a boat with an electric motor in 1845, but it wasn't until 1837 when Thomas and Emily Davenport patented the first motor in the US that the promise of electro-mechanical machinery was seen as the next big leap forward.\nRudimentary programming allows storing a bill on a recipe database and importing it into an assembler.\nThe blue region around assemblers and recipe databases indicates the data transfer area.</PRF_CoreTierII.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_CoreTierIII.label>binary system</PRF_CoreTierIII.label>
  <PRF_CoreTierIII.description>1초와 0초가 충분한 경우 모든 것은 1초와 0초의 연결로 설명할 수 있습니다.</PRF_CoreTierIII.description>
  <PRF_CoreTierIII.discoveredLetterTitle>Binary system</PRF_CoreTierIII.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_CoreTierIII.discoveredLetterText>Refinements to machinery allow sophisticated machines, such as those that self-correct (get faster the more times they complete a job), drills with object recognition to only mine what you want and the first mechanite swarm technologies.\nMechanite machines interact with a couple of random tiles in the area every second.</PRF_CoreTierIII.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_CoreTierIV.label>quantum bit technology</PRF_CoreTierIV.label>
  <PRF_CoreTierIV.description>현실 자체의 양자적 특성을 활용하여 기하급수적으로 더 까다로운 계산 문제를 해결합니다.</PRF_CoreTierIV.description>
  <PRF_CoreTierIV.discoveredLetterTitle>Quantum bit technology: Tier 4 unlocked</PRF_CoreTierIV.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_CoreTierIV.discoveredLetterText>Qubit technology is all about advanced computing, high-end machines and technology, this might even be on the brink of insanity? whats next?!¤%.\nDrop us suggestions on our Workshop page or Discord.\n\nThanks for playing!</PRF_CoreTierIV.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_BeltsI.label>basic conveyor networks</PRF_BeltsI.label>
  <PRF_BeltsI.description>The continual movement of raw resources and final products within a factory is tedious but crucial. Understanding the fundamentals of conveyor networks is very important to fulfill manufacturing needs and determine production rates.</PRF_BeltsI.description>
  <PRF_BeltsII.label>basic sorting systems</PRF_BeltsII.label>
  <PRF_BeltsII.description>공장의 적절한 구역으로 물건을 보내면 공장 배치가 간소화되고 다양화됩니다.\n 잠금 해제: 단순 배출기, 재배구역 배출기 및 일반 벨트를 위한 분배기.</PRF_BeltsII.description>
  <PRF_BeltsIII.label>advanced sorting systems</PRF_BeltsIII.label>
  <PRF_BeltsIII.description>Sophisticated logistical implementation allows for advanced item sorting.\nUnlocks: Wall and underground belts, splitters, smart hoppers, as well as Mk.II, angle, and wall pullers.</PRF_BeltsIII.description>
  <PRF_BasicDrones.label>basic drone knowledge</PRF_BasicDrones.label>
  <PRF_BasicDrones.description>The first pilotless vehicles were built during the First World War. These early models were launched by catapult or flown using radio control. Much has changed since then and drones are now used for more common tasks.\nThis sets the base stats of drones to level 10.</PRF_BasicDrones.description>
  <PRF_BasicDrones.discoveredLetterTitle>About: Drones are now level 10</PRF_BasicDrones.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_BasicDrones.discoveredLetterText>You now have basic knowledge about drones and can now start to utilize them for different tasks.\nThis will set any drone's base level to 10.\nUnless other settings for a specific drone station are specified.</PRF_BasicDrones.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_ImprovedDrones.label>improved drone engines</PRF_ImprovedDrones.label>
  <PRF_ImprovedDrones.description>Further improvements for drones have now enabled the use of more drones and with greater control over tasks they can perform.\nThis sets the base stats of drones to level 15.</PRF_ImprovedDrones.description>
  <PRF_ImprovedDrones.discoveredLetterTitle>About: Drones are now level 15</PRF_ImprovedDrones.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_ImprovedDrones.discoveredLetterText>You have upgraded your drones with better engines and batteries and as such they now do jobs even more efficiently.\nThis will set any drone's base level to 15.\nUnless other settings for a specific drone station are specified.</PRF_ImprovedDrones.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_AdvancedDrones.label>advanced drone AI</PRF_AdvancedDrones.label>
  <PRF_AdvancedDrones.description>Perfectly aerodynamics higher power engines and AI have created a perfectly balanced super drone that will perform tasks better than most pawns ever will.\nThis sets the base stats of your drones to level 20.</PRF_AdvancedDrones.description>
  <PRF_AdvancedDrones.discoveredLetterTitle>About: Drones are now level 20</PRF_AdvancedDrones.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_AdvancedDrones.discoveredLetterText>You have upgraded your drones with advanced AI cores, this will let them do their tasks better than most humans will do.\nThis will set any drone's base level to 20.\nUnless other settings for a specific drone station are specified.</PRF_AdvancedDrones.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_AutonomousMining.label>automatic quarries</PRF_AutonomousMining.label>
  <PRF_AutonomousMining.description>Make buildings that can extract random minerals and rocks from deep underground. Most forms of automated mining can attract the attention of insectoids, so keep an eye out for that.</PRF_AutonomousMining.description>
  <PRF_AutonomousMining.discoveredLetterTitle>정보: 조립기 소개</PRF_AutonomousMining.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_AutonomousMining.discoveredLetterText>You have now researched the auger drill. With this, you have unlocked the tier 1 auto miner.\nThis miner will mine up random items over time, it can start infestations just like vanilla drills.\n\nThe tier 2 miner is the same type of device, it's just faster and will mine steel instead of slag.\n\nTier 3 has two types of miners.\nType one is a random miner like the previous generations, it will mine random rare ores with no stone chunks.\nType two is a new type of miner where you can set exactly what type of ore you want. It will mine mainly that one, but will have a chance to mine junk and rare ores too.\n\nIf you want to enable un-balanced mode for miner and unlock all mod-added ores you can change it in mod settings.</PRF_AutonomousMining.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_AutonomousMiningII.label>improved automatic quarries</PRF_AutonomousMiningII.label>
  <PRF_AutonomousMiningII.description>Build more advanced auto-miners that work more quickly, though they'll still attract infestations at the same rate.</PRF_AutonomousMiningII.description>
  <PRF_AutonomousMiningIII.label>deep core quarries</PRF_AutonomousMiningIII.label>
  <PRF_AutonomousMiningIII.description>Build two more advanced forms of miners. One will only produce resources with no stone, and one allows you to target-mine specific resources. Neither of the tier 3 miners will draw infestations thanks to the advanced technology they use to dampen vibrations.</PRF_AutonomousMiningIII.description>
  <PRF_SALResearchI.label>S.A.L autonomous crafting I</PRF_SALResearchI.label>
  <PRF_SALResearchI.description>숙련된 노동을 수행할 수 있도록 기계를 프로그래밍하는 방법을 배웁니다.</PRF_SALResearchI.description>
  <PRF_SALResearchI.discoveredLetterTitle>정보: S.A.L 자동화 로봇들</PRF_SALResearchI.discoveredLetterTitle>
  <PRF_SALResearchI.discoveredLetterText>With this research you have unlocked S.A.L automation robots.\nThese are placeable robots that you attach to a workbench where a human would stand, and then they will start doing work on that bench.\n\nThe name "S.A.L" is a tribute to the original SAL mod, from whence Project RimFactory is descended.</PRF_SALResearchI.discoveredLetterText>
  <PRF_SALResearchII.label>S.A.L 자율 제작 II</PRF_SALResearchII.label>
  <PRF_SALResearchII.description>자동화 기계 프로그래밍에 대한 이해를 높이고, 기계들이 더 빠르고, 더 좋게, 그리고 보다 확실하게 만들 수 있습니다.</PRF_SALResearchII.description>
  <PRF_SALResearchIII.label>S.A.L specialization</PRF_SALResearchIII.label>
  <PRF_SALResearchIII.description>Further advancements in machine programming will allow you to begin to specialize your S.A.L machines into performing specific roles more efficiently.</PRF_SALResearchIII.description>
  <PRF_SALResearchIV.label>S.A.L art I</PRF_SALResearchIV.label>
  <PRF_SALResearchIV.description>하이퍼컴퓨팅과 신경망 연결을 배워서, 기계가 적절한 반제품 예술품을 제작할 수 있도록 합니다.</PRF_SALResearchIV.description>
  <PRF_SALResearchV.label>S.A.L art II</PRF_SALResearchV.label>
  <PRF_SALResearchV.description>오버클러킹과 결합하여 신경망이 훨씬 빠르게 반응하도록 하여 기계에서 생성된 예술품의 품질을 크게 향상시킵니다.</PRF_SALResearchV.description>
  <PRF_SALResearchVII.label>S.A.L 자율 조리</PRF_SALResearchVII.label>
  <PRF_SALResearchVII.description>자동 조립기가 요리사를 효율적으로 교체할 수 있도록 손재주와 정확성을 충분히 제공하는 방법을 배웁니다.</PRF_SALResearchVII.description>
  <PRF_SALResearchVI.label>S.A.L autonomous overclocking I</PRF_SALResearchVI.label>
  <PRF_SALResearchVI.description>General S.A.L machines often work too slowly and can result in slow production. Upgrading them with the ability to overclock their operating systems will result in faster production speeds at the cost of some item quality.</PRF_SALResearchVI.description>
  <PRF_SALResearchVIII.label>S.A.L autonomous overclocking II</PRF_SALResearchVIII.label>
  <PRF_SALResearchVIII.description>Increases to servo speed and internal visualization computers allow this S.A.L crafter to work even faster than before. Henry Ford would be proud.</PRF_SALResearchVIII.description>
  <PRF_SALGodlyCrafting.label>S.A.L prime crafting</PRF_SALGodlyCrafting.label>
  <PRF_SALGodlyCrafting.description>수많은 시간동안의 엄격한 연구 끝에 마침내 최고의 기계를 얻을 수 있습니다. 프라임 제작은 대부분의 인류에게 알려지지 않은 제조 수준을 소개합니다. 현존하는 가장 진보된 사회만이 이러한 공학의 기적을 달성했지만, 그 대가는 무엇입니까?</PRF_SALGodlyCrafting.description>
  <PRF_Crates.label>wooden stockpile crates</PRF_Crates.label>
  <PRF_Crates.description>Rudimentary storage boxes allow many stacks of items to stay organized and space-efficient.</PRF_Crates.description>
  <PRF_SteelCrates.label>steel stockpile crates</PRF_SteelCrates.label>
  <PRF_SteelCrates.description>Stronger materials allow for improved storage space.</PRF_SteelCrates.description>
  <PRF_StorageIO.label>Thornsworth holographic storage</PRF_StorageIO.label>
  <PRF_StorageIO.description>The holographam artist Thornsworth produced masterpieces for many years despite gradually developing blindness. When holographic data storage was perfected, he was instrumental in developing holographic item storage.\nAllows items to be stored in a digital storage unit, which can transmit and receive wirelessly to any I/O port on the map.\n\nYou will be missed, Thornsworth.</PRF_StorageIO.description>
  <PRF_StorageIO_II.label>improved wireless storage</PRF_StorageIO_II.label>
  <PRF_StorageIO_II.description>무선 스토리지의 발전. \nI/O 배출기를 건설할 수 있습니다 (그 이상, 예정).</PRF_StorageIO_II.description>
</LanguageData>
