<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <SmokeleafCultivation.label>smokeleaf cultivation</SmokeleafCultivation.label>
  <SmokeleafCultivation.description>The process of seperating the parts of the smokeleaf plant. Produces smokeleaf buds, seeds and hemp fibers. Allows joints to be rolled.</SmokeleafCultivation.description>
  <SmokeleafProcessing.label>smokeleaf processing</SmokeleafProcessing.label>
  <SmokeleafProcessing.description>Cooks will be able to experiment in the kitchen, creating smokeleaf edibles.  It has also been noticed that the fibers of the smokeleaf plant might be able to be used to make a some new materials, if we had the proper tools to use.</SmokeleafProcessing.description>
  <IndustrialSmokeleafCultivation.label>industrial smokeleaf cultivation</IndustrialSmokeleafCultivation.label>
  <IndustrialSmokeleafCultivation.description>Develop the cultivation table, letting workers process smokeleaf in larger quantities and in new forms.  A storage facility is made for easier access to trimming tools. And a new grow lamp is also invented that is a little easier on the electricity bill.</IndustrialSmokeleafCultivation.description>
  <IndustrialSmokeleafProcessing.label>industrial smokeleaf processing</IndustrialSmokeleafProcessing.label>
  <IndustrialSmokeleafProcessing.description>New fuel and fabric can be created from smokeleaf fibers. New culinary recipes are available. Researchers begin to unlock and understand the medical properties of the drug. CBD extraction will be possible.</IndustrialSmokeleafProcessing.description>
  <AdvancedSmokeleafCultivation.label>advanced smokeleaf cultivation</AdvancedSmokeleafCultivation.label>
  <AdvancedSmokeleafCultivation.description>Develop new machinery to aid in the growth and processing of smokeleaf.</AdvancedSmokeleafCultivation.description>
  <AdvancedSmokeleafProcessing.label>advanced smokeleaf processing</AdvancedSmokeleafProcessing.label>
  <AdvancedSmokeleafProcessing.description>New methods available for extracting and concentrating the compounds of smokeleaf. Because of this, new edibles and recreational forms are available. An advanced renewable metal can also be crafted.</AdvancedSmokeleafProcessing.description>
  <SmokeleafPharmacology.label>smokeleaf pharmacology</SmokeleafPharmacology.label>
  <SmokeleafPharmacology.description>Isolate the beneficial compounds of smokeleaf and unlock the power to apply them in modern medical science with no ill side effects.</SmokeleafPharmacology.description>
  <SmokeleafGlittertech.label>smokeleaf glittertech</SmokeleafGlittertech.label>
  <SmokeleafGlittertech.description>Highly advanced uses for smokeleaf byproducts will be developed after in-depth study by our researchers.</SmokeleafGlittertech.description>
</LanguageData>